Guide to the Allegheny Observatory Records, 1850-1977 UA.5.1
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Letterpress Books of Directors/Acting Directors, 1862-1910; II.
  - Samuel Pierpont Langley, 1884-1889; 1.
    - Samuel Langley, 1884-1887 (Box 30, Volume 2)
      - Phillips and Co. Pittsburgh, PA. Submitting order for elastic rubber to be used in aerodynamic experimentation, 1p., March 28, 1887; 152.
      - Brashear, J.G. Allegheny, PA. Working drawings for Whirling Table nearly completed, 1p., March 30, 1887; 153.
      - Tennant, George B. Pittsburgh, PA. Modification in specification of Whirling Table, 1p., March 30, 1887; 154.
      - Specification of the Whirling Machine, A.D.S., 2p., ca. March; 155.
      - Christern, F.W. New York, NY. Request for information pertaining to cost of the publication, L'Aeronaute, 1p., April 12, 1887; 156.
      - Christern, F.W. New York, NY. Request for price of publication Histoire des Ballons by Gaston Fissandier, L., 1p., April 21, 1887; 157.
      - Brashear, J.A. Allegheny, PA. Sketch of [Whirling Table?], 1p., April 25, 1887; 158.
      - Brashear, J.A. Allegheny, PA. Experiments indicate that double wheel model [aircraft] should be discontinued and replaced by Renaud aircraft. Sketch of Renaud aeroplane enclosed, 3p., April 26, 1887; 159.
      - Queen and Co. Philadelphia, PA. Wishes to obtain a tachometer or tachograph. [Probably related to aerodynamic experimentation, Ed.], 1p., April 26, 1887; 160.
      - Phillips and Co. Pittsburgh, PA. Please state cost, width, and length of roll of elastic rubber to execute order for rubber 1/8 and also 1/4 inch thickness, 1p., April 27, 1887; 161.
      - U.S. Army, Chief Signal Officer. Washington, DC. Concerning the absolute temperature of the earth's surface and the measurement of solar radiation, 3p., April 27, 1887; 162.
      - Concerning the "true color of the sun", A.D.S., 2p., ca. April; 163.
      - Fire Department. Allegheny, PA. Complaints concerning inaccurate time signals to be directed to the Allegheny Observatory, L., 1p., May 7, 1887; 164.
      - Tennant, George B. Philadelphia, PA. Check enclosed in payment for services rendered in preparation of drawings and estimates for a Whirling Table, 1p., May 18, 1887; 165.
      - U.S. Treasury Dept., Bureau of Statistics. Washington, DC. A list of Langley's scientific papers published by the U.S. Government, L., 1p., May 18, 1887; 166.
      - Brashear, J.A. Allegheny, PA. Sketch of aeroplane [barely legible, Ed.], 2p., May 20, 1887; 167.
      - Christern, F.W. New York, NY. Second request for ordering publication L'Aeronaute, 1p., May 25, 1887; 168.
      - Thaw, William. Pittsburgh, PA. Annual Report 1886/87 of the Director, 6p., ca. May; 169.
      - Rowe, Charles O. Titusville, PA. Response to inquiry concerning time service, 1p., June 2, 1887; 170.
      - Rowe, Charles O. Titusville, PA. A "description of the devices for striking time signals" L. 2p., June 3, 1887; 171.
      - Ballot, Buys. Ultrecht, Holland. Expresses interest on status of research in the area of lunar heat, 1p., June 13, 1887; 172.
      - Clerke, Agnes M. London, England. Concerning studies on absorption of the earth's atmosphere, 3p., June 13, 1887; 173.
      - Warner and Swasey. Cleveland, Ohio. Request for a siderostat driving clock be repaired as soon as possible, L., 1p., June 14, 1887; 174.
      - Stoletow, A. Moscow, Russia. Concerning radiation analysis by means of heat spectrum and aid of bolometer, 2p., June 17, 1887; 175.
      - Queen and Co. Philadelphia, PA. Second request for ordering information pertaining to tachometer and tachograph, 1p., June 18, 1887; 176.
      - Hazen, Allen. Washington, DC. Erecting a Whirling Table of "exceptional size" to carry out experiments in anemometry and the resistance of air to bodies in motion including railroad trains. Expects to make experiments in fall with a locomotive and platform cars, 2p., June 25, 1887; 177.
      - Woodwell and Co. Pittsburgh, PA. Wishes to obtain a tachometer and dynamometer, 2p., June 25, 1887; 178.
      - Brashear, J.A. Allegheny, PA. Concerning the mounting of two large reflecting mirrors at the Allegheny Observatory, 3p., June 29, 1887; 179.
      - District Telegraph Co. Pittsburgh, PA. Wire from which railroads are receiving time signals running into several jewelry stores, 2p., June 29, 1887; 180.
      - Metzgar, Henry. Pittsburgh, PA. Serious complaints from railroads for not receiving time signals, 1p., July 2, 1887; 181.
      - Abbe, Cleveland. Washington, DC. Request for a chronograph cylinder to be used for aerodynamic experimentation, 2p., July 5, 1887; 182.
      - Rotch, A. Lawrence. Request for data on the varying velocity of the wind during short intervals of time, e.g., every quarter of minute or less. Further that Rotch request attach a chronograph to an anemometer which would record electronically the varying velocities on a uniformly revolving board, 2p., July 5, 1887; 183.
      - Rowe, Charles O. Titusville, PA. Request for a pole to be set up close to the Observatory with wires leading to the top of chromograph [Probably be used in measurement of wind velocity, Ed.], 1p., July 5, 1887; 184.
      - Grunow, William. West Point, NY. Request fro sketch of collimator and prism table, 3p., July 8, 1887; 185.
      - White, James. Glasgow, Scotland. Inquiry as to when galvanometer will be completed. No acknowledgement of letter of March 19, 1887, 1p., July 8, 1887; 186.
      - Queen and Co. Philadelphia, PA. Purchasing tachometer no. 4 running from 25 to 3000 revolutions per minute, 1p., July 12, 1887; 187.
      - Rotch, A. Lawrence. Acknowledgement of receipt of chronographic record. Requests that record should in the future be obtained on a time scale, ten times as long, "so that the changes from minute to minute can be recognized during an hour or so", 1p., July 13, 1887; 188.
      - Rowe, Charles O. Titusville, PA. Acknowledgement of receipt of pole used in connection with chromograph, 1p., July 14, 1887; 189.
      - Description of "self recording apparatus to be placed at end of arm of great Whirling Table", 8p., July 15, 1887; 190.
      - Glassford, W.O. Prescott, Arizona. Corcerning the variations of solar radiation from hour to hour, L., 3p., August 3, 1887; 191.
      - Ohio Meteorological Bureau. Youngstown, OH. Diagram of the positions of Venus, Earth, and Sun on August 14, 1887, L., 1p., August 19, 1887; 192.
      - Langley, J.A. Washington, DC. Status of research at Allegheny Observatory. Whirling Table not yet erected, L., 5p., September 10, 1887; 193.
      - Reid, H.F. Cleveland, OH. Concerning strongest current a bolometer will bear, L., 1p., September 15, 1887; 194.
      - Reid, H.F. Cleveland, OH. Specifications of bolometer, no. 1, L., 1p., September 28, 1887; 195.
      - Grunow, William. West Point, NY. Wishes to test collimator and prism table, 1p., November 8, 1887; 196.
      - De Motte, John B. Greencastle, IN. Brief description of bolometer manufacture and usage, L., 1p., November 9, 1887; 197.
      - Peal, S.E. Naharain, Sigsagar, India. Lunar research nearly completed. Findings to be issued by U.S. Government Printing Office, 1p., November 9, 1887; 198.
      - Barus. Determination of the relation between emission and temperature by spectrobolometric methods, 1p., November 23, 1887; 199.
      - Hall and Sons. Buffalo, NY. Request for a dozen crucibles. Sketch enclosed, 1p., November 23, 1887; 200.
    - Samuel Langley and Frank Very, 1887-1888 (Box 30, Volume 3)
      - Smyth, Thomas H. Toronto, Canada. A bolometer might be devised to measure the temperature of a liquid, 2p., January 26, 1888; 1.
      - Thaw, William. Pittsburgh, PA. Requests permission to allow J.A. Brashear to use thirteen-inch equatorial to conduct his own research, T.L.S., 2p., January 27, 1888; 2.
      - De Motte, John B. Greencastle, IN. Forwarding information concerning bolometer theory and place and name of manufacturer of bolometer, 2p., January 31, 1888; 3.
      - De Motte, John B. Greencastle, IN. Sending two pamphlets containing illustrations and full descriptions of the bolometer and its theory, 2p., January 31, 1888; 4.
      - Reid, H.F. Cleveland, OH. Acknowledge of receipt of description of experiments with the bolometer by Professor H.F. Reid of the Case School of Applied Science, January 31, 1888; 5.
      - Brashear, J.A. Allegheny, PA. Brashear directed to prepare a scale for the "White" galvanometer. Also a request for 4 galvanometer mirrors of 1 meter values of curvature, 1p., February 2, 1888; 6.
      - Brashear, J.A. Allegheny, PA. Langley authorizes Brashear to use 13 inch equatorial of Allegheny Observatory for his own researches, 2p., February 2, 1888; 7.
      - White, James. Glasgow, Scotland. Generally pleased with finish and solardarity of galvanometer. However, hinges to enable magnets to be unclasped from glass rod were disregarded, 1p., February 2, 1888; 8.
      - Brashear, J.A. Pittsburgh, PA. Preparation of a box of seasoned pine to hold the new "White" galvanometer, L., 3p., February 3, 1888; 9.
      - Grunow, William. West Point, NY. Final modifications of dynometer - chronograph made by Brashear in Pittsburgh, T.L.S., 2p., February 16, 1888; 10.
      - Langely, S.p., Washington, DC. Very conducting experiments with humming birds, L., 2p., February 25, 1888, 11.
      - Brashear, J.A. Allegheny, PA. "Langley wishes to have made for the Smithsonian Institute a rocking case with plate glass top, mirror at sides and bottom and spring stands to hold twenty humming birds" Sketch enclosed, L., 2p., February 29, 1888; 12.
      - Abney, W. de. Wivelislile London, England. Concerning atmospheric absorption of acceptance of post at Smithsonian Institute, 6p., February; 13.
      - Sheaffer, C.W. Pittsburgh, PA. "Scarcely any current in the telegraph line", L., 1p., March 1, 1888; 14.
      - Mead, Elwood. Ft. Collins, CO. Provides ordering information for actinometer and spectrobolometer. Supplies instructions for use of instruments in place of aforementioned ones, 2p., March 5, 1888; 15.
      - Rood. Wishes to obtain data concerning the "brightness of the normal eye to the pure spectrum colors", 1p., March 14, 1888; 16.
      - Batchalde, A. Pelham, NH. Concerning the relationship between lightning and the fall of meteoric dust, L., 1p., March 21, 1888; 17.
      - Witchell. "Taking measures of the intensity of different colored lights taking for instance red, yellow, blue, or any number of other spectral colors from the same sources and same prism, and trying the comparative intensities of each by noting the relative illuminating powers by suitable tests for the normal eye", 1p., March 30, 1888; 18.
      - Pennsylvania Railroad. Altoona, PA. Posting a copy of a printed circular describing time signal distributions, L., 1p., April 5, 1888; 19.
      - McIntire, Johnston. Allegheny, PA. Langley wishes a box to be constructed to house stuffed humming birds. Sketch enclosed, L., 2p., April 28, 1888; 20.
      - Brashear, J.A. Allegheny, PA. Wishes to have a 20 inch mirror of one meter focus silvered, 1p., May 11, 1888; 21.
      - Grunow, William. West Point, NY. Concerning construction of a spectrobolometer which must be completed within ten months, 2p., May 11, 1888; 22.
      - Hale. No French engines for utilizing solar heat more recent than those of Mouchot, exhibited in 1878. French commission report engine not feasible to operate. J. Ericson's engine not economically feasible to operate, 1p., May 11, 1888; 23.
      - McIntire, Johnston. Allegheny, PA. Modifications in construction of box to contain stuffed humming birds, L., 1p., May 11, 1888; 24.
      - Reuben, Levi. New York, NY. Acknowledgement of receipt of the book, Travels in the Air. Langley states also with regard to inequalities in the distribution of clouds and rain that he cannot render a judgment on such a meteorological question, 1p., May 15, 1888; 25.
      - Thomson, W. Philadelphia, PA. Request for the title of the best treatise on color vision, L., 1p., May 24, 1888; 26.
      - Thaw, William. Pittsburgh, PA. Statement of cash receipts and expenditures of the Allegheny Observatory also includes annual report 1887/88 on the "scientific labors of the Observatory" [one page not legible, Ed.], T.L.S., 6 p., ca. May; 27.
      - Grunow, William. West Point, NY. No response concerning construction of spectrobolometer. Langley soon to depart for Europe, 1p., June 23, 1888; 28.
      - Crova, A. Montpelliar, Vermont. Concerning a new value of the solar constant. Description of galvanometer usage and sketch of galvanometer enclosed, 3p., June 25, 1888; 29.
      - Notes on the History of the Doctrine of Radiant Energy, A.D. S., 10p., ca. June; 30.
      - Grunow, William. West Point, NY. Dynomemterchronograph found to be a very satisfactory instrument but a few modifications necessary, T.L.S., 1p., July 12, 1888; 31.
      - Ticknor and Co. Boston, MA. Possibility of publishing a cheap edition of the New Astronomy in the U.S. and a costly edition in England, 1p., August 13, 1888; 32.
      - Peal, S.E. Naharani, Sibsagar, India. Commentary on the nature of the moon's rays, L., 2p., August 15, 1888; 33.
      - American Journal of Science. New Haven, CT. Enclosed copy of article entitled "Energy and Vision" for November publication, 1p., September 28, 1888; 34.
      - American Journal of Science. New Haven, CT. Concerning the return of the proof copy of an article entitled "Energy and Vision", 1p., October 23, 1888; 35.
      - London, Edinburgh, and Dublin Philosophical Magazine. Forwarding proof of an article on "Energy and Vision", which was expected to appear in the American Journal of Science for November, 1888, 1p., October 23, 1888; 36.
      - Gibbs, Wilcott. Newport, RI. Langley prepared to make a personal examination of disposition of Bache fund for purposes specified on researches in solar physics; description of research in progress, 2p., November 5, 1888; 37.
      - Brashear, J.A. Allegheny, PA. Langley providing Brashear with assistance in determining the "dispersive power" of a crown lens, 2p., November 9, 1888; 38.
      - Accounts payable for October and November, 1888, L., 1p., Allegheny, PA, November 22, 1888; 39.
      - American Journal of Science. New Haven, CT. Request for 500 copies in paper covers of History of a Doctrine, 1p., December 3, 1888; 40.
      - Ballot, Buys. Ultrecht, Holland. Will post in a few days an abstract of the paper, "On the Solar and Lunar Spectrum," published in the December 1888 issue of the Journal of Science, 2p., December 3, 1888; 41.
      - Turner, S.E. Pittsburgh, PA. Wishes to have the "shaft of the turn table made frictionless", 2p., December 3, 1888; 42.
    - Samuel Langley, Frank Very, and James Keeler, 1889-1891 (Box 30, Volume 4)
      - [Memorandum] Authorization for removal of pieces of apparatus, which were the personal property of Mr. W. Thaw, to the personal charge of Langley. Signed by W. Thaw, A.D.S., 2p., June 19, 1889; 1.
      - Annual Report [1888/89] of the Director of the Allegheny Observatory, A.D.S., 4p., ca. June; 2.
    - James Keeler, 1887-1894 (Box 31, Volume 1)
    - Frank Very and James Keeler, 1892-1895 (Box 31, Volume 2)
    - James Keeler, John Brashear, F.L.O. Wadsworth, and Henry Harrer, 1895-1901 (Box 31, Volume 3)
    - John Brashear, 1898-1900 (Box 32, Volume 1)
    - F.L.O. Wadsworth, 1901-1902 (Box 32, Volume 2)
    - F.L.O. Wadsworth, Frank Schlesinger, and Frank Bailey, 1902-1906 (Box 32, Volume 3)
    - F.L.O. Wadsworth, 1896-1902 (Box 33, Volume 1)
    - Frank Schlesinger, 1907-1910 (Box 34, Volume 1-3)
- Directors/Acting Directors Miscellany, 1863-1978; III.
  Series III contains publications, correspondence, articles, notes, manuscripts and other miscellaneous materials arranged by Director.
  - Samuel Langley, 1.
    - Publications
      - Articles by Langley (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Bound Volumes of Langley Works (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Samuel Pierpont Langley - His Early Academic Years of Western University of Pennsylvania, by Wallace Beardsley, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Rules and Regulations, by the London Chathan and Dover Railway Company, 1863 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Bound volume of Langley publications, most dealing with the Mt. Whitney expedition (Box 35a, Folder 5)
      - Resolution passed by the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution on Langley's death, 1906 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence
      - Correspondence of Langley relatives, 1908-1909, 1911, 1942 (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Handwritten Instructions in user of "waste book", September 15, 1890 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Notes and Manuscripts
      - Notes on Newton's Optics (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Untitled (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Frank Very, 2.
    - Articles by Very (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Articles about Very (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Notes and Manuscripts (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - James Keeler, 3.
    - Articles by Keeler (Box 36, Folder 14)
      - John Brashear, 4.
        - Articles by Brashear (Box 36, Folder 18)
        - Articles about Brasheas (Box 36, Folder 19)
        - Catalogs of John A. Brashear, Co., Ltd. (Box 36, Folder 20)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 36, Folder 21)
          - F.L.O. Wadsworth, 5.
            - Articles by Wadsworth (Box 36, Folder 22)
            - Notes and Manuscripts (Box 37, Folder 23-36)
            - Notes and Manuscripts, continued (Box 38, Folder 37-48)
            - Miscellaneous (Box 38, Folder 49)
    - Articles about Keeler (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Unknown (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Frank Schlesinger, 6.
    - Publications by Schlesinger (Box 38, Folder 50)
    - Notes and Manuscripts (Box 38, Folder 51)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 38, Folder 52)
  - Heber Curtis, 7.
    - Articles by Curtis (Box 38, Folder 53)
    - Articles about Curtis (Box 38, Folder 54)
    - Notes and Manuscripts (Box 38, Folder 55)
    - Notebook on Spanish (Box 39, Folder 56)
    - Notebook on Mayan (Box 39, Folder 57)
    - Cash Account for Sproul Expedition through July 21, 1923 (Box 39, Folder 58)
  - Frank Jordan, 8.
    - Articles by Jordan (Box 39, Folder 59)
    - Articles about Jordan (Box 39, Folder 60)
    - Notes and Manuscripts (Box 39, Folder 61-66)
    - Journals (2 volumes), 1908-1909 (Box 39, Folder 67)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 39, Folder 68)
  - Nicholas Wagman, 9.
    - Articles by Wagman (Box 39, Folder 69)
    - Open House at the Observatory, 1951-1965 (Box 39, Folder 70)
- Correspondence of Affiliated Astronomers, 1886-1972; IV.
  The following correspondence is available on microfilm and in its original form. For a detailed list of correspondents consult Indexes to the Microfilmed Correspondence of Directors, Acting directors, and Selected Astronomers Among the Records of the Allegheny Observatory.
  - Frank Bartko, 1960-1971; 1.
    - A-I (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - J (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - K-U (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - New Material Added, 2013
      - Frank Bartko Correspondence (Box 74, Folder 16)
  - Wallace Beardsley, 1958-1970; 2.
    - A-Be (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Bi-Bu (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - C-D (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - E (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - F-Ga (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Gr-H (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - I-L (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - M-R (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - S (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - T-Z (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - University of Pittsburgh (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - New Material Added, 2013
      - Wallace R. Beardsley Correspondence (Box 74, Folder 17)
  - Kievin Burns, 1920-1958; 3.
    - Ab-Ad (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - Ai (Box 74, Folder 17)
    - Ak (Box 74, Folder 18)
    - Akl-Alt (Box 74, Folder 19)
    - Alu-American Asso (Box 74, Folder 20)
    - American Ast (Box 74, Folder 21)
    - American C-As (Box 74, Folder 22)
    - Bab-Bal (Box 74, Folder 23)
    - Ban-Bar (Box 74, Folder 24)
    - Be-Bo (Box 74, Folder 25)
    - Bra-Bri (Box 74, Folder 26)
    - Brou (Box 74, Folder 27-36)
    - Brow-Bu (Box 41, Folder 37)
    - Ca-Ci (Box 41, Folder 38)
    - Cl (Box 41, Folder 39)
    - Co-Cn (Box 41, Folder 40)
    - Da-Di (Box 41, Folder 41)
    - Do-Du (Box 41, Folder 42)
    - Ea (Box 41, Folder 43-46)
    - Eb-El (Box 41, Folder 47)
    - Em-Fi (Box 41, Folder 48)
    - Fl-Gae (Box 41, Folder 49)
    - Gal-Gr (Box 41, Folder 50)
    - Hak-Has (Box 41, Folder 51)
    - Har (Box 41, Folder 52-55)
    - Haw-He (Box 41, Folder 56)
    - Hi-Ho (Box 41, Folder 57)
    - Hu (Box 41, Folder 58)
    - Hy-Ins (Box 41, Folder 59)
    - Ins (Box 41, Folder 60-61)
    - Int-Jac (Box 41, Folder 62)
    - Jam-Ki (Box 41, Folder 63)
    - Kie (Box 41, Folder 64-66)
    - Kin-La (Box 41, Folder 67)
    - Le-McL (Box 41, Folder 68)
    - McM (Box 41, Folder 69-70)
    - Ma (Box 42, Folder 71)
    - Meg (Box 42, Folder 72-86)
    - Mellon (Box 42, Folder 87-89)
    - Mellor-Mer (Box 42, Folder 90)
    - Mer (Box 42, Folder 91-92)
    - Mey-Mi (Box 42, Folder 93)
    - Moo (Box 42, Folder 94)
    - Mor (Box 42, Folder 95)
    - Mu-Pes (Box 42, Folder 96)
    - Pen-Pr (Box 42, Folder 97)
    - Po-Ru (Box 42, Folder 98)
    - Ru (Box 42, Folder 99)
    - Saint (Box 42, Folder 100)
    - Sa-Sca (Box 43, Folder 101)
    - Schl (Box 43, Folder 102-105)
    - Schu-Shu (Box 43, Folder 106)
    - She-Sil (Box 43, Folder 107)
    - Sit (Box 43, Folder 108-110)
    - Sk-Sm (Box 43, Folder 111)
    - Sp-St (Box 43, Folder 112)
    - Su (Box 43, Folder 113-127)
    - Swa (Box 43, Folder 128)
    - Swa-Ti (Box 43, Folder 129)
    - To-U (Box 43, Folder 130)
    - Va-Ve (Box 44, Folder 131)
    - Ve (Box 44, Folder 132)
    - Vy-Warg (Box 44, Folder 133)
    - Warn-We (Box 44, Folder 134)
    - Wi-Wo (Box 44, Folder 135)
    - Wr-Wy (Box 44, Folder 136)
    - Y-Z (Box 44, Folder 137)
    - University of Pittsburgh, B-Cl (Box 44, Folder 138)
    - University of Pittsburgh, Co (Box 44, Folder 139-142)
    - University of Pittsburgh, F-G (Box 44, Folder 143)
    - University of Pittsburgh, L-Pl (Box 44, Folder 144)
    - University of Pittsburgh, Pr-Sec (Box 44, Folder 145)
    - University of Pittsburgh, Sec (Box 44, Folder 146-149)
    - University of Pittsburgh, Si-V (Box 44, Folder 150)
  - Zaccheus Daniel, 4.
    - A-B (Box 44, Folder 151)
    - C-D (Box 44, Folder 152)
    - F-H (Box 44, Folder 153)
    - J (Box 44, Folder 154)
    - L-P (Box 44, Folder 155)
    - R-Sa (Box 44, Folder 156)
    - Sc (Box 44, Folder 157)
    - Sk-W (Box 44, Folder 158)
    - University of Pittsburgh (Box 44, Folder 159)
- Affiliated Astronomers Miscellany, no date; V.
  - Kievin Burns, 1.
    - Articles by Burns (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Articles about Burns (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Notes and Manuscripts (Box 45, Folder 3-12)
  - Zaccheus Daniel, 2.
    - Articles by Daniel (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Articles about Daniel (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Material Relating to Daniel's Education (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - J.H. Kiewiet de Jonge, 3.
    - Articles by de Jonge (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Notes and Manuscripts (Box 45, Folder 18-22)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 46, Folder 23)
  - Wallace Beardsley, 4
    - Stellar Radial Velletities- a report made with a grant from the U.S. Navy, along with related correspondence and financial information (Box 46, Folder 24)
  - Robert Kemper, 5.
    - Eclipse Six (June 30, 1954), July 8, 1954 (Box 46, Folder 25)
- Administrative Files, 1858-1977; VI.
  - University of Pittsburgh (Western University of Pennsylvania prior to 1909), 1.
    - Catalogs for Astronomical Deptartment, 1883-1889 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Five items to R. B. Carnahan, attorney for the University, from William Thaw, Samuel Langley and James Keeler on dispute over property boundaries of the observatory, 1885 (Box 46, Folder 2)